Julien Plu

My name is Julien Plu, I am passionated by different things. My strongest passion are computers since I had my first one at 6 years old. Besides computers, I also like doing sport, such as tennis that I practiced for 11 years or scuba diving that I still practice since more than 20 years. Another passion is music, I love playing guitar, I play mainly hard rock and metal music but I also like any kind of other music. As most of the persons of my generation, I love video games since my youngest age, any kind of video games. The last but not the least of my passions is, traveling, every year I try to visit two or three countries abroad France, mainly for doing scuba diving.



Contact Info

in linkedin.com/in/julienplu

@ plu.julien@gmail.com

**** +33 6 70.14.19.68

≥ 34 rue Lenine

93170, Bagnolet, France

Portfolio

- Attps://jplu.github.io
- https://github.com/jplu

Skills

Research Areas

Natural Language Processing Machine Learning Deep Learning Semantic Web

Languages

Java

Python

 G_0

C and C++

Frameworks

Java: Spring, Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, Stanford CoreNLP Python: Tensorflow, Numpy, Pandas, scikit-learn

Go: Gin, cobra, viper

Web Development

VueJS

Operating Systems

Linux Windows

Mac OS

Miscellaneous

Docker Kubernetes Google Cloud Platform

EXPERIENCES

2018-04 present

Applied Scientist

Paris, France Leboncoin

· My role at Leboncoin is to investigate new approaches and ideas involving machine learning in order to improve the experience of our users.

2018-01 2018-03

R&D Engineer

Mondeca Paris France

• Help to develop the internal software of the company on Semantic Web technologies.

2014-07 2017-12

2013-04

2014-06

PhD candidate

Furecom

♀ Sophia-Antipolis, France • My PhD topic is to extract lexical units (entities) from textual documents to disambiguate them against Web

resources contained in a knowledge base and in an adaptive manner. This adaptivity is on the language of the processed texts, the used knowledge base and the textual content that can be either formal text (journalistic style) or informal text (microposts).

Software Engineer

Aepsilon ♀ Sophia-Antipolis, France

· Consultant at Orange on semantic Web, NLP and Machine Learning technologies for their in-house Web search engine. My works was about to implement a natural language question module. Take a question in natural language and turn it into a SPARQL query to provide an answer and to put DBpedia technologies into Orange production pipeline. I also prototyped a French entity relation extraction system from crawled Web pages in order to populate a knowledge base.



SELECTED PROJECTS

2014-07 present

ADEL

- · ADEL stands for ADaptive Entity Linking. It is the output of my thesis. It is developed in Java (Spring, Spring boot and Spring Cloud)
- The code can be found at: https://github.com/jplu/ADEL

2016-12 present

DeepNER

- · DeepNER is a Named Entity Recognition approach that uses a Deep Learning architecture developed during my PhD. It is developed in Python with Tensorflow
- The code can be found at: https://github.com/jplu/DeepNER

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Computer Science 2017

Furecom ♥ Sophia-Antipolis, France

2012 Master in Computer Science (AI speciality)

University of Montpellier II ♥ Montpellier, France

License in Computer Science

♥ Montpellier, France University of Montpellier II

Scientific baccalaureate 2017

High School Joliot Curie

Sète, France

2010